A Guide to the Lyman Creighton Craig papers, Rockefeller University Faculty FA134
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Professional correspondence, 1950 1952-1974; 2
  - B-Bi
    - Barr, D.P. Craig invited to du Vignaud dinner after Harvey lecture, 2 letters (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Barry, G.T. At RIMR 1946-1958. Evaluation of and curriculum vitae, 1964-1968; 9 letters (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Batich, C. Curriculum vitae, 1 letter (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Battersby, A.R. At RIMR 1950-1951, 1953-1957 1968-1969; 28 letters (Box 3, Folder 1)
      Professional correspondence between friendly colleagues.
      Includes employment recommendation for; numerous Battersby holographs and Battersby et al reprints.
    - Beaber, C., 2 letters (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Beams, J.W., 3 letters (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Bearn, A., 4 letters (Box 3, Folder 1)
      About A.M. Gotto with Gotto curriculum vitae.
    - Beaven, G.H., 1 letter (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Becker, E.W., 1 letter (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Becker, I., 2 letters (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Becker, R., 1 letter (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Beckman Instruments Inc., 1955 1965; 2 letters (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Beintema, J.J., 4 letters (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Bell, P.H., 1 letter (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Benjamin, W.A., 1 letter (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Bennett, R.B., 1 letter (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Bennett, T.P. RU student, 10 letters (Box 3, Folder 1)
      Includes Craig and committee thesis evaluation and recommendations for.
    - Bergel, F., 1 letter (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Beringer, F.M., 3 letters (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Beroza, M., 6 letters (Box 3, Folder 1)
      Includes Beroza and Bowman ms "Extraction of insecticides for cleanup and identification" with Craig comments.
    - Beyerman, H.C., 4 letters (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Bier, M., 2 letters (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Biffen, F.M., 2 letters (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Binkley, W.W., 2 letters (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Biochemical Preparations, 1955-1963; 14 letters (Box 3, Folder 2)
      member of editorial board. Includes agendas of meetings, various membership lists; tentative table of contents of Vol. VI and Vol VII of. Correspondent: Carl S. Vestling.
    - Biochemistry (148), 1961-1974 (Box 3, Folder 3)
      Primarily reviews of mss submitted for publication.
      Includes correspondence on Craig mss; introductory pamphlet to Biochemistry; H. Neurath letter of congratulations on Craig Fisher Award; 1974 Jan becomes member of editorial advisory board of.
  - Bi-Bo (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Biopolymers, 4 letters
      Reviews of 2 mss.
    - Bittman, R., 4 letters
      Includes Bittman et al reprints; photocopied figures; graphs.
    - Bixler, H.J., 2 letters
    - Blankenhorn, D.H., 1 letter
    - Bleich, H. At RU 1971-1974, 13 letters
      Includes Curriculum vitae; bibliography; recommendations for and Bleich et al reprint.
    - Bloomfield, V. Recommendation for T. Schleich, 2 letters
    - Bock, R., 2 letters
    - Bockman, Richard. RU student, 1969-1971; 9 letters
      Includes Bockman 1969 progress report; 1969-70 annual report and recommendations for.
    - Bodanszky, M., 2 letters
    - Boheim, G., 4 letters
    - Boissonnas, R.A., 2 letters
    - Borowska, Z. At RU 1962-, 11 letters
      Includes curriculum vitae, bibliography and Borowska reprint.
    - Bourguet, J., 2 letters
    - Bovery, F.A., 2 letters
    - Bowen, W.J., 2 letters
    - Bower, B., 2 letters
  - Br-By (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Bradford, E. Recommendation for Dorothy A. Segner, 1 letter
    - Brandt, W.W. Suggestions for speakers at NSF Summer conference on chromatography, 4 letters
    - Braunitzer, G., 1962-1971; 29 letters
      Correspondence between friendly colleagues.
      Correspondence indicates Braunitzer's frequent visits to RU. Includes correspondence about Meetings: 1963 Athens, Greece; and 1971 Liege, Belgium; and 1963 Munich, Germany. Also includes Fujiki curriculum vitae and reprints.
      [See also under: CCD: Subject file in box no. 15].
    - Brennan, T.F. Curriculum vitae, 1 letter
    - Brewer, J.M., 2 letters
    - Bricas, E., 2 letters
    - Brink, N.F., 1 letter
    - Brodie, B.B. 1972 July 24 San Francisco, Calif. International Pharmacology dinner honoring B.B. Brodie, 6 letters
    - Brown, B., 2 letters
    - Brown, G.B., 2 letters
    - Brown, G.H., 1 letter
    - Brugsch, J., 2 letters
    - Brunfeldt, K., 1 letter
      [See also under: CCD: Subject file in box l5].
    - Bryan, R.F., 2 letters
    - Bull, H., 3 letters
    - Burachik, M. At RU 1967-1968, 12 letters
    - Burford, A., 2 letters
    - Burke, G.E. Recommendation for Ms. McNamara, 1 letter
    - Burma, D.P., 5 letters
      Includes bibliography.
    - Burrell, J., 2 letters
    - Bush, M.T., 1953 1962 1973; 27 letters
      Includes: Meeting: 1973 Jan NYC NY Academy of Sciences conference on drug-binding protein.
    - Busson, Dr., 2 letters
    - Butenandt, A., 3 letters
    - Bycroft, B.W., 1972; 1 letter
      Meeting: 1972 July/Aug? Boston, Mass Peptide meeting "Work relating to momycin and other cyclic peptides".
  - C-Co (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Calif. Polytechnic State University, 1 letter
    - Calif. State University, Fresno, 1 letter
    - Calif. State University, Northridge, 1 letter
    - Calloway, N., 2 letters
    - Campo, A.J., 1 letter
    - Canadian Breweries Ltd., 1 letter
    - Canadian Journal of Biochemistry, 2 letters
      Review of Bailey and Hurst ms.
    - Canadian Journal of Chemistry, 2 letters
      Review of Edwards and Singh ms.
    - Carnegie, P.R., 4 letters
    - Carpenter, F.H., 1953 1956; 4 letters
    - Carter, H., 1 letter
    - Caspary, W., 2 letters
    - Cassidy, H.G., 1956 February 9; 5 letters
      Includes 1956 Feb 9 New Haven ACS Section "Some experiments with partial dialysis and extraction"; includes abstract.
    - Cerami, A. RU Faculty. Recommendation for a Helen Hay Whitney Foundation fellowship, 2 letters
    - Chakravarti, R.N., 1 letter
    - Chambers, E.L. Recommendation for D.W. Kupke, 3 letters
    - Chang, D.R., 1 letter
    - Chang, Z.J., 1 letter
    - Chanley, J.D. Curriculum vitae; bibliography, 3 letters
    - Chapman, D., 5 letters
    - Chase, M.W., 1 letter
    - Chemapec Inc., 1 letter
    - Cheng, P. 1963-1971. 1956-1963 at RF virus laboratories, 15 letters
      Includes recommendations for employment and ASBC membership. Also includes curriculum vitae and bibliographies.
    - Chernoff, A.I., 2 letters
    - Chibnall, A.C., 3 letters
    - Chow, S-W. Curriculum vitae, 2 letters
    - Chudon, Z.L. Curriculum vitae, 1 letter
    - Ciba Corp., 1964 February; 5 letters
      Includes: Lecture: 1964 Feb Summit, N.J. Ciba Corp lecture series on chemical separations "on countercurrent and dialysis".
    - Ciba Ltd
      [See under: Lab data: Substance "P" in box no].
    - Claesson, S., 1 letter
    - Clark, A.H., 2 letters
    - Clark, L.M. Use of Glen Rock, NJ JHS gym for boy scout meeting, 2 letters
    - Clarkson, B. Dialysis unit at Sloan-Kettering, 2 letters
    - Clauser, H.J., 4 letters
    - Cleary, J.T., 2 letters
    - Cochran, D.W. Curriculum vitae with bibliography, 2 letters
    - Codington, J.F., 3 letters
    - Coe, E.L. Seminar: 1966 Apr 19 Chicago, Ill, Northwestern University Medical School on "Differential dialysis", 1966 April 19; 4 letters
    - Cohen, B.I. Curriculum vitae, 2 letters
    - Cohen, L.A., 2 letters
    - Cohn, E.J., 1 letter
    - Cohn, W.L., 2 letters
    - Cole, R.D. Recommendation for Guggenheim Foundation fellowship, 2 letters
      [See also under: Stracher, Alfred in box no. 13].
    - Collins, F.D., 1 letter
    - Colowick, S.P., 5 letters
    - Columbia University. Craig handwritten list of 10 most outstanding men in Craig's field of work for Columbia University development plan committee, 2 letters
    - Coniglio, J.G., 2 letters
    - Conoly, J.H. Mrs. Recommendations for Cook, R. (2), 5 letters
    - Cope, A.C., 2 letters
  - Co-Cu
    - Cort, J.H., 5 letters (Box 4, Folder 1)
      Includes grant application to Pop Council for G. Schaechtelin.
    - Corwin, A.H., 3 letters (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Coulson, C.B., 3 letters (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Cowan, J.C., 2 letters (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Cowburn, D. RU 1973-, 9 letters (Box 4, Folder 1)
      Curriculum vitae; bibliography; 1973 research proposal with Craig to Reproductive physiology group.
    - Craig, David. Brother, 1956; 15 letters (Box 4, Folder 1)
      Correspondence about 1956 published chapter by L.C. and David Craig "Laboratory extraction and countercurrent distribution".
      [See also under: Mss: Not listed in bibliography in box no. 31].
    - Creighton, T.E., 2 letters (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Crestfield, A. Recommendation for, 1 letter (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Cross, D.R., 4 letters (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Cross, R.A., 2 letters (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Cunningham, L.W., 2 letters (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Curtis, G.G. Jr., 1 letter (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Chen, H.C. At RU 1964-1972, 1963-1973; 60 letters (Box 4, Folder 2)
      Curriculum vitae; bibliographies; graduate school transcript; recommendations for and ASBC membership; 1972 paper with Craig at Federation meeting.
      [See 1972 mss not listed in bibliography in box no].
    - Ciba Foundation, 1953-1955; 42 letters (Box 4, Folder 3)
      Includes: Meetings: 1952 London, Ciba Foundation symposium on chemical structure of protein "The importance and use of suitable fractionation procedures for structural studies with proteins" [Title from bibliography]. Indications are Craig discussion participant; 1955 June 21-23 London, Ciba Foundation symposium on the nature and actions of the internal secretions of the pancreas. Includes programs, membership lists and Dr. Craig's discussion in session on "the chemical and physical properties of insulin and glucagon" and 2 items with J. Mller, Ciba Pharmaceutical, Basel.
    - Commercial Solvents Corp., 1951 1956-1974; 65 letters (Box 4, Folder 4)
      Correspondence primarily with W.F. Phillips; some with P. Hidy on collaborative work on bacitracin; Dr. Craig consultant 1967 July 1-1968 June 30 for; some correspondence with others on bacitracin. Also includes Seminar: 1970 Nov 6 Terre Haute, Ind. Commercial Solvent Corp. "The use of analytical dialysis for characterization of chemical compounds" and papers by others.
  - D-du (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Damerel, C.I., 2 letters (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Davidson, J.K., 2 letters (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Davies, M., 2 letters (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Deal, C.H. Suggestions for 1963 Gordon Research conference, 2 letters (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Deber, C.M., 5 letters (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - de Haen, P., 6 letters (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Dekker, E.E., 2 letters (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Dekker, M., 2 letters (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - de Laszlo, H., 2 letters (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Denber, H.C.B. At RU 1971 July-1972 January, 13 letters (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Denney, D., 1 letter (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Deulofeu, V., 2 letters (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Deuticke, H.J. 2 items in German, 3 letters (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - De Witt, C.C., 3 letters (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Dhar, A.K. Curriculum vitae, 2 letters (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Dhar, M.L., 1 letter (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Dimililer, I., 2 letters (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Dimler, R.J., 2 letters (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Dingman, J.F., 2 letters (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Dion, A.S., 2 letters (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Dirheimer, G., 2 letters (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Dixon, J., 2 letters (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Djerassi, C., 2 letters (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Dole, V.P. RU Professor, 1 letter (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Do Minh, T. Curriculum vitae; bibliography; college and graduate school transcripts, 3 letters (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Dooley, S., 2 letters (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Drost-Hansen, W. Lecture: 1972 Nov 3 NYC NY Academy of Sciences "on thin-film dialysis", 1972 November 3; 4 letters (Box 4, Folder 5)
      Includes Drost-Hansen bibliography.
    - Dubnoff, J. Renomination of J.D. Gregory for Eli Lilly award, 3 letters (Box 4, Folder 5)
      includes Gregory bibliography.
    - Dubos, R.J. RU Professor, 2 letters (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Duncan, W.H. Apartment rental recommendation for T.P. King, 2 letters (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Du Pont, E.I. & Co. Seminar: 1954 Mar 4 Newark, Del. Grasselli Chemicals Dept of du Pont on "Fractionation methods designed for the isolation and structural study of biologically active principles", 1954 March 4; 8 letters (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Durnick, T.J. Curriculum vitae, 3 letters (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Durrum Instrument Corp., 1 letter (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Dutton, H.J., 1952-1955 1967-1969; 8 letters (Box 4, Folder 5)
      Includes support for AOCS annual award in lipid chemistry for.
    - du Vigneaud, V., 1953-1955 1960-1963; 9 letters (Box 4, Folder 5)
      Professional correspondence between colleagues. Includes Craig congratulations on du Vigneaud Nobel Prize.
  - Eaker, David. RU graduate student, 1960-1968; 31 letters (Box 4, Folder 6)
    Includes 1962 June presentation for Ph. D by Craig with convocation program; curriculum vitae and recommendations for.
  - E-Es (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Eagle, H., 1 letter
    - Eastman Kodak Co
      [See under: Interscience Publishers in box no].
    - E-C Apparatus Co
      [See under: Raymond, S. in box no. 12].
    - Edelman, G.M. RU Professor. Recommendations for ASBC membership and employment, 5 letters
    - Edsall, John T. Items concerning distribution of reprints and about false statement in National Academy subcommittee of physical effects of the sonic boom report, 1962-1968; 8 letters
      Includes fact sheet 15 "Correlation of public reaction to sonic-boom-induced property damage" by Citizens League Against the Sonic Boom. Indications on Aug 2, 1968 Craig signed form to have NAS correct statement, 2 August 1968.
    - Eich, S., 2 letters
    - Eigen, M., 2 letters
    - Einstein, E.R., 4 letters
    - Eisenberg, L. At RU 1959 -. Biographical material for employment of, 8 letters
      [See also under: Rosen, P. in box no. 1].
    - Elbaum, D. Curriculum vitae, 2 letters
    - Elderfield, R.C., 1953-1956 1963; 7 letters
      Includes comments about T.P. King.
    - Elliott, T.H., 1 letter
    - Elrick, H., 2 letters
    - Elving, P.J., 1956 1962; 7 letters
    - Elsevier Scientific Publishing Co., 2 letters
    - Encyclopedia of Chemistry, 1 letter
    - Encyclopedia of Industrial Chemical Analysis. Ms: Countercurrent distribution". Published in 1966, 5 letters
    - Encyclopedia of Polymer Science and Technology, 1 letter
    - Englander, W., 3 letters
    - Engle, L.L., 2 letters
    - Englund, Paul T. RU graduate student, 1963-1968; 19 letters
      Includes recommendations for; student annual reports 1962-63; 1963-64 and Dr. Craig's progress report on.
    - Erlanger, B.F., 2 letters
    - Esso Research and Engineering Co., 1968-1974; 20 letters
      Correspondence primarily with N.N. Li. Includes items on Craig acting as consultant to Esso and Lecture: 1968 Oct 31 Linden, NJ Esso on "Separations based on size and conformation"; abstract; lecture announcement.
  - F-Fu (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Fales, H.M., 3 letters (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Fang, F.T., 2 letters (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Fang, H.C., 2 letters (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Fasman, G.D. 1963; 1972. Seminar: 1963 Nov 5 Waltham, Mass. Brandeis University 1963-64 fall semester colloquia series on "The use of membrane diffusion studies of conformation", 3 letters (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Federation Proceedings, 1 letter (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Feeley, F., 1 letter (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Felix, K., 2 letters (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Fenske, M.R., 2 letters (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Ferber, K.K., 1952-1953; 8 letters (Box 4, Folder 8)
      Includes: Lectures: 1953 Feb Buffalo, NY Foster lecture series University of Buffalo consists of 1 afternoon and 1 evening lecture and Craig Feb 16, 1953 letter listing all European labs visited in 1952 Autumn? (presents lectures at most).
    - Ferry, C.W., 3 letters (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Few, A.V., 7 letters (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Field, F.H. RU Professor, 15 letters (Box 4, Folder 8)
      Correspondence between colleagues primarily about Mass Spectrometry service laboratory operated by Dr. Field.
    - Filachek, L., 2 letters (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Firschein, H.E., 5 letters (Box 4, Folder 8)
      Includes curriculum vitae and bibliography.
    - Fischbach, H., 2 letters (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Fischer, L., 2 letters (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Fisher, M.H., 2 letters (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Fletcher, H.G., 3 letters (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Flett, L., 1 letter (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Flodin, P., 1 letter (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Florida International University, 1 letter (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Folkers, K., 2 letters (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Ford, R.A., 2 letters (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Foster, A.B., 1 letter (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Foster, J.F., 4 letters (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Fox, S.W., 1953-1956 1959 1965; 10 letters (Box 4, Folder 8)
      Professional correspondence between friendly colleagues. Includes recommendations for others.
    - Franconi, C., 2 letters (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Franke, N.W., 2 letters (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Fredericq, E., 4 letters (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Frediani, H.A., 2 letters (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Free, C.A., 4 letters (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Freedman, M.H. (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - French, D., 1954 1970-1974; 11 letters (Box 4, Folder 8)
      Professional correspondence between friendly colleagues. Includes recommendation for R.M. Hixon for ACS midwest award.
    - Fresco, J.R., 2 letters (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Fried, J., 2 letters (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Frieden, E., 14 letters (Box 4, Folder 8)
      Correspondence between colleagues. Includes bibliography.
    - Frieden, E.H., 2 letters (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Friedman, H.S. Curriculum vitae, 2 letters (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Friedrich, M. 1948 Munich lecture "The chemistry of polypeptide antibiotics", 2 letters (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Fryshov, 2 letters (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Fuhr, I. Evaluation of A.A. Kozinski NIH grant application, 2 letters (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Fujiki, H., 2 letters (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Fuson, R.C., 1 letter (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Fisher, J.D., 1961 September 4-9; 33 letters (Box 4, Folder 9)
    Collaborators on ACTH work.
    Correspondence about paper and Meeting: 1961 Sept 4-9 Lake County, Calif. Laurentian hormone conference Rasmussen and Craig "The chemistry, biochemistry, and physiology of the parathyroid hormone". Includes program and membership list.
  - G-Gl (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Gagnaire, D., 2 letters
    - Gambull, C.M., 2 letters
    - Garrison, R.E., 2 letters
    - Garrett, E.R., 2 letters
    - Gascoigne, J.A., 2 letters
    - Gates, W.C., 2 letters
    - Geddes, A.J., 2 letters
    - Gerald, P.S., 2 letters
    - Gerhardt, P., 2 letters
    - Gosh, A.C., 3 letters
      Curriculum vitae and bibliography.
    - Ghosh, S.B., 8 letters
      Examines thesis of.
    - Giddings, J.C. Editor: Separation Science, 1 letter
    - Gilman, H., 1953-1954 1962 1973-1974; 14 letters
    - Girlhaven, Inc., 3 letters
      Includes biographical sketch of L.C. Craig.
    - Gish, D.T., 2 letters
    - Glazko, A.J., 2 letters
    - Glickson, J.D., 15 letters
  - Go-Gu (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Goldman, C., 2 letters (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Golumbic, C. At RI, 1942-1945; 9 letters (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Goodall, M., 1 letter (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Goodman, M., 1 letter (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Goodfriend, T.L., 2 letters (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Goodson, L.H. Supports nomination of R.M. Hixon for ACS Spencer award, 3 letters (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Gordon, G.S., 3 letters (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Gordon, M., 2 letters (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Gorkin, V.L., 2 letters (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Gould, R.G., 1 letter (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Governor House, 1 letter (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Grady, H.J., 2 letters (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Gray, C.H., 4 letters (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Gray, G.A., 2 letters (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Green, J.H. Lectures: ca 1969 October 15 Ridgefield, Conn. New England Institute lectures and discussions, 1 letter (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Greengard, P., 2 letters (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Gregor, H.P., 4 letters (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Gregory, John D. RU Faculty, ca 1949; 1956; 1962; 1966. At RU 1947-49; 1957, 1949-1966; 12 letters (Box 5, Folder 2)
      Includes Gregory lecture for RU student course in biochemistry. Also includes recommendations for employment and NIH Research Development award.
    - Grell, E., 2 letters (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Gressley, G.M., 3 letters (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Griffin, J.H., 8 letters (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Griffis Faculty Club, 1 letter (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Griffith, W.H., 2 letters (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Groeschel, A.H. Recommendation for J.D. Di John, 3 letters (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Grotte, G. Curriculum vitae, 1 letter (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Grover, P.L., 2 letters (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Guillemin, R., 6 letters (Box 5, Folder 2)
      Professional correspondence between colleagues.
    - Gupta-Bhaya, P., 2 letters (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Galardy, Richard E. RU student, 29 letters (Box 5, Folder 3)
    Includes letters of recommendation for deferments and others; typescript of Ph. D presentation by Craig; some typescripts of assorted papers, 1 with referees remarks.
  - Gibbons, Wm. A. At RU 1966-1974, 75 letters (Box 5, Folder 4)
    Curriculum vitae and bibliography; nomination for Sloan research fellowship and other recommendations. Includes correspondence about operation of spectroscopy lab; also copy of 1971 June 18 paper at San Francisco.
  - Goldstein, Jack. At RU, 1959-1966; 48 letters (Box 5, Folder 5)
    Curriculum vitae and bibliography. Includes recommendation for and nomination for ASBC membership; typescript of T.W. Schleich Ph. D presentation by J. Goldstein.
  - Guidotti, Guido. RU student, 1960-1970; 30 letters (Box 5, Folder 6)
    Correspondence includes recommendations for and nomination for Harvey Society membership. Also includes typescript of presentation for Ph. D by Craig; curriculum vitae and bibliography.
  - Gross, Erhard. At RI 1959 January-May, 1959-1974; 41 letters (Box 5, Folder 7)
    Curriculum vitae and bibliographies. Includes nominations for ASBC membership and "Preis biochemische analytik".
  - H-He (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Hadd, H.E., 3 letters
      About countercurrent distribution instrument.
      [See also under: Post, Otto in box no. 11].
    - Haidemenakis, E.D. 1971 International Science Foundation conference invitation to be principal speaker; declines, 5 letters
      Includes brochure.
    - Haller, W., 1973 May 24; 5 letters
      Includes Haller 1973 May 24 RU lecture "Controlled pore glass chromatography: mechanical and biological applications".
    - Ham, R.G., 2 letters
    - Hammes, G.G., 4 letters
    - Handler, P., 1955 1964; 2 letters
      Includes congratulations on Handler election to NAS.
    - Harcourt, Brace & World Inc., 4 letters
      About use of CCD apparatus photo for "The Human Body".
    - Hardwicke, J., 2 letters
    - Harfenist, E.J. At RIMR 1951-1953?; RU 1961-1969?, 1961-1972; 5 letters
      Includes recommendations for...
    - Harfenist, M. Lectures: 1961 Oct 13 ACS NY section organic discussion group "The organic chemistry of protein molecules" with abstract; and 1962 Sept 20 Tuckahoe, NY Wellcome research laboratories on "countercurrent distribution (?)", 1961-1962 October 13; 5 letters
    - Harris, J.I., 11 letters
      Professional correspondence between collaborators.
    - Harris, J.J. At RU, 1970-1973; 18 letters
      Curriculum vitae; bibliography and recommendations for.
    - Harris, S., 3 letters
    - Harrison, S., 2 letters
    - Harte, R.A., 2 letters
    - Hartmann, G., 1 letter
    - Harwalker, V.R., 3 letters
    - Hartwig, J.H., 2 letters